He just landed the gig of his life: 5th grade.
School of Rock is a comedy, music film directed by Richard Linklater.
Fired from his band and hard up for cash, guitarist and vocalist Dewey Finn finagles his way into a job as a fifth-grade
substitute teacher at a private school, where he secretly begins teaching his students the finer points of rock 'n' roll.
The school's hard-nosed principal is rightly suspicious of Finn's activities.
But Finn's roommate remains in the dark about what he's doing.
Dewey Finn, played by Jack Black.
Rosalie Mullins, played by Joan Cusack.
Ned Schneebly, played by Mike White.
Patty Di Marco, played by Sarah Silverman.
Summer Hathaway, played by Miranda Cosgrove.
Zack, played by Joey Gaydos Jr..
School of Rock (titled on screen as The School of Rock) is a 2003 American comedy film
directed by Richard Linklater, produced by Scott Rudin and written by Mike White.
The film stars Jack Black, Joan Cusack, White and Sarah Silverman.
Black plays struggling rock guitarist Dewey Finn, who is fired from his band and
subsequently poses as a substitute teacher at a prestigious prep school.
After witnessing the musical talent of the students, Dewey forms a band of fifth-graders to
attempt to win the upcoming Battle of the Bands and use his winnings to pay his rent.
School of Rock was released on October 3, 2003, by Paramount Pictures,
grossing $131 million worldwide on a $35 million budget.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with
praise for Black's performance and humor.
It was the highest-grossing music-themed comedy of all time
until the release of Pitch Perfect 2 in 2015.
A stage musical adaptation opened on Broadway in December 2015, and a television
adaptation aired for three seasons on Nickelodeon from March 2016 to April 2018.
The film explores themes of high school, rock 'n' roll,
musician, music competition, substitute teacher.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.